

#### Contact



+31681076415



willemvanderpijl@hotmail.com



Hardinxveld-Giessendam, Netherlands



28-11-1996

### Skills

- Design Tools: Figma (Auto-layout),
  Adobe Suite, Sketch, Firefly AI,
  Lottie
- Prototyping: High-fidelity
  Prototypes, Interaction design,
  Iterative design
- User Research: Business Analysis,
  (On-site) User testing, A/B testing
- Design Systems: DesignOps,
  Component Libraries, SDX
- Technical skills: Angular, HTML,
  CSS, VS Code, Git
- Bonus skills: Photo/Video editing,
  Animation, Motion design

## Languages

• **Dutch:** Native

• English: Professional working

• German: Passive

## Portfolio

www.cinewillem.nl (Photo/Video focused)

# Willem van der Pijl

UX/UI Designer & Business Analyst

## **About Me**

I am a UX/UI designer with three years of professional experience in UX/UI. Prior to that, I worked as a Software Engineer for two years. The combination of technical knowledge and design skills means I can be a bridge between the technical world and the business world, effectively communicating with developers about technical possibilities. Additionally I love videography & animation. Useful for explainer videos or web based Lottie animations.

## Experience



Jul. 2021 - Present

#### **Swisscom** • UX/UI Designer & Business Analyst

Recently, I focused on transforming customer-oriented and logistic processes for Physical Swisscom stores. Collaborated closely with the business side and provided detailed feedback to Software Engineers by personally running and inspecting the build solution. I conducted valuable on-site user testing whenever possible.



Jul. 2019 - Jun. 2021

#### **NGTI** • Full-Stack Developer

Working with modern JavaScript frameworks like Angular and Vue I was able to play a part in developing customer facing web applications. I was also able to utilize my skills as a motion designer by animating and implementing expressive Lottie animations.



Feb. 2019 - Jul. 2019

#### **NGTI** • Graduation Intern Software Engineer

This internship was focused on my Graduation Project Sketch2Vue, building a Sketch plugin that could automatically convert designs from Sketch into Vue components. This meant I had to go in-depth with Developers and figure out their way of working within Vue.js.



Aug. 2017 - Feb. 2018

## Plexsys B.V. • Intern Web development & UX/UI Design

Worked at Plexsys B.V. as a designer and software engineer for Degree-n, creating user flows for their products and enhancing the user experience with Motion design.



Okt. 2016 - Jul. 2017

#### Microsoft • Talent Engineer

.NET C# Web development for start-ups connected to the Microsoft Young Talent program.

## Education



2015-2019

Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences

Bachelor, Computer Science



2018 - 2019

Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences

Minor, Game Design & Development